{
    "glossary": {
        "title": "1983",
        "season": "Höst",
        "glossaryList":[
            {
                "number": "1",
                "question": "bronker",
                "a": "luftrör",
                "b": "blokärl",
                "c": "nervbanor",
                "d": "hjärnceller",
                "e": "muskelvävnader",
                "answer": "luftrör"
            },
            {
                "number": "2",
                "question": "pretentioner",
                "a": "överdrifter",
                "b": "försök",
                "c": "anspråk",
                "d": "motsättningar",
                "e": "förmåner",
                "answer": "anspråk"
            },
            {
                "number": "3",
                "question": "eternell",
                "a": "plågoande",
                "b": "insektssamling",
                "c": "kyrkobyggnad",
                "d": "evighetsblomma",
                "e": "tygsort",
                "answer": "evighetsblomma"
            },
            {
                "number": "4",
                "question": "trägen",
                "a": "besvärlig",
                "b": "flitig",
                "c": "retlig",
                "d": "långrandig",
                "e": "pålitlig",
                "answer": "flitig"
            },
            {
                "number": "5",
                "question": "dementera",
                "a": "avslöja",
                "b": "lova",
                "c": "fördärva",
                "d": "granska",
                "e": "förneka",
                "answer": "förneka"
            },
            {
                "number": "6",
                "question": "emotionell",
                "a": "påhittig",
                "b": "regelbunden",
                "c": "tillgjord",
                "d": "bestämd",
                "e": "känslomässig",
                "answer": "känslomässig"
            },
            {
                "number": "7",
                "question": "streber",
                "a": "förtryckare",
                "b": "kvacksalvare",
                "c": "uppåtsträvare",
                "d": "uppfinnare",
                "e": "ersättare",
                "answer": "uppåtsträvare"
            },
            {
                "number": "8",
                "question": "bordlägga",
                "a": "sammankalla",
                "b": "framlägga",
                "c": "besluta",
                "d": "avslå",
                "e": "uppskjuta",
                "answer": "uppskjuta"
            },
            {
                "number": "9",
                "question": "eklatera",
                "a": "avskeda",
                "b": "färdigställa",
                "c": "upplösa",
                "d": "offentliggöra",
                "e": "avbryta",
                "answer": "offentliggöra"
            },
            {
                "number": "10",
                "question": "stärbhus",
                "a": "konkursbo",
                "b": "familjeföretag",
                "c": "släktgård",
                "d": "dödsbo",
                "e": "adelsätt",
                "answer": "dödsbo"
            },
            {
                "number": "11",
                "question": "revers",
                "a": "kontoutdrag",
                "b": "köpebrev",
                "c": "återköp",
                "d": "skuldsedel",
                "e": "avkastning",
                "answer": "skuldsedel"
            },
            {
                "number": "12",
                "question": "stursk",
                "a": "trotsig",
                "b": "enfaldig",
                "c": "lättstött",
                "d": "illasinnad",
                "e": "självisk",
                "answer": "trotsig"
            },
            {
                "number": "13",
                "question": "dekadans",
                "a": "förfalla",
                "b": "besvikelse",
                "c": "fattigdom",
                "d": "avvikelse",
                "e": "likvärdighet",
                "answer": "förfalla"
            },
            {
                "number": "14",
                "question": "retroaktiv",
                "a": "tillbakabildad",
                "b": "tillbakavisande",
                "c": "tillbakasatt",
                "d": "tillbakadragen",
                "e": "tillbakaverkande",
                "answer": "tillbakaverkande"
            },
            {
                "number": "15",
                "question": "dogm",
                "a": "upprop",
                "b": "lärosats",
                "c": "utmärkelse",
                "d": "befallning",
                "e": "utmaning",
                "answer": "lärosats"
            },
            {
                "number": "16",
                "question": "avhysa",
                "a": "inställa",
                "b": "hindra",
                "c": "bekämpa",
                "d": "vräka",
                "e": "svika",
                "answer": "vräka"
            },
            {
                "number": "17",
                "question": "auditorium",
                "a": "utställning",
                "b": "åhörarkrets",
                "c": "beundrarskara",
                "d": "föreläsning",
                "e": "visning",
                "answer": "åhörarkrets"
            },
            {
                "number": "18",
                "question": "nebulosa",
                "a": "solförmörkelse",
                "b": "halvklot",
                "c": "stjärnbild",
                "d": "stjärntöcken",
                "e": "norrsken",
                "answer": "stjärntöcken"
            },
            {
                "number": "19",
                "question": "applicera",
                "a": "anbringa",
                "b": "överlämna",
                "c": "uppskatta",
                "d": "utpeka",
                "e": "inspruta",
                "answer": "anbringa"
            },
            {
                "number": "20",
                "question": "kolerisk",
                "a": "löjlig",
                "b": "hetsig",
                "c": "långsam",
                "d": "vänlig",
                "e": "uppspelt",
                "answer": "hetsig"
            },
            {
                "number": "21",
                "question": "placenta",
                "a": "moderkaka",
                "b": "avgjutning",
                "c": "takmålning",
                "d": "majsmjöl",
                "e": "jordegendom",
                "answer": "moderkaka"
            },
            {
                "number": "22",
                "question": "sonor",
                "a": "färgsprakande",
                "b": "ljudlös",
                "c": "klangfull",
                "d": "långvarig",
                "e": "uttrycksfull",
                "answer": "klangfull"
            },
            {
                "number": "23",
                "question": "alludera",
                "a": "avsluta",
                "b": "nedvärdera",
                "c": "tilldela",
                "d": "anförtro",
                "e": "anspela",
                "answer": "anspela"
            },
            {
                "number": "24",
                "question": "konsternerad",
                "a": "förargad",
                "b": "förtvivlad",
                "c": "försummad",
                "d": "förödmjukad",
                "e": "förbryllad",
                "answer": "förbryllad"
            },
            {
                "number": "25",
                "question": "fysionomi",
                "a": "andning",
                "b": "styrka",
                "c": "utseende",
                "d": "själsliv",
                "e": "sjukdomsbild",
                "answer": "utseende"
            },
            {
                "number": "26",
                "question": "opportunism",
                "a": "anpasslighet",
                "b": "kärnfullhet",
                "c": "anspråksfullhet",
                "d": "avundsamhet",
                "e": "belåtenhet",
                "answer": "anpasslighet"
            },
            {
                "number": "27",
                "question": "subversiv",
                "a": "envis",
                "b": "omstörtande",
                "c": "foglig",
                "d": "känslig",
                "e": "inställsam",
                "answer": "omstörtande"
            },
            {
                "number": "28",
                "question": "restituera",
                "a": "begränsa",
                "b": "instämma",
                "c": "upprepa",
                "d": "återbetala",
                "e": "avbeställa",
                "answer": "återbetala"
            },
            {
                "number": "29",
                "question": "polemik",
                "a": "meningsutbyte",
                "b": "värdighet",
                "c": "rörlighet",
                "d": "minispel",
                "e": "taktfasthet",
                "answer": "meningsutbyte"
            },
            {
                "number": "30",
                "question": "kverulera",
                "a": "skryta",
                "b": "låtsas",
                "c": "klaga",
                "d": "plåga",
                "e": "vägra",
                "answer": "klaga"
            }
        ]
    }
}